<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
               "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<refentry id="tlm-intro">
  <refmeta>
    <refentrytitle>Introduction</refentrytitle>
  </refmeta>

  <refsect1>
    <title>What is TLM?</title>
    <para>
        TLM is a daemon that handles user logins in a multi-user, multi-seat system by
        authenticating the users through PAM, and setting up, launching, and tracking user
        sessions.
    </para>
    <para>
        TLM daemon itself does not include any UI for interacting with
        the users; any such interaction is handled through TLM's authentication plugin system (see
            <link linkend="TlmAuthPlugin">TlmAuthPlugin</link>).
        TLM can be configured to log-in a default ("guest") user when no other
        user is logged in at a specific seat.
    </para>
    <para>
        TLM also exports a <link linkend="gdbus-org.tizen.Tlm.Login">D-Bus API</link>, that can be used to log in, log out and
        switch users on a seat.
    </para>
    <para>
        Under examples, tlm-ui demonstrates the usage of tlm daemon's dbus
        interface for login, logout and switch user functionality. Login
        object with root access is exported at TLM_DBUS_ROOT_SOCKET_ADDRESS
        which can be used to login, logout and switch any user.
        TLM_DBUS_ROOT_SOCKET_ADDRESS can be fetched as a variable from package
        configuration file tlm.pc.
        Besides whenever a user is logged in, a dbus login object is also
        exported which can be used for 'logout-user' and 'switch-user'
        functionalities by that user. The dbus object can be accessed at
        TLM_DBUS_SOCKET_PATH/&lt;seat_id-uid&gt; by the user (uid) who is logged
        in at the seat (seat_id).
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
      <title>Plugin development</title>
      <para>
          Plugins should be named "libtlm-plugin-&lt;plugin_name&gt;.so" and
          they should contain a
          "tlm_&lt;plugin_type&gt;_plugin_&lt;plugin_name&gt;_get_type"
          symbol that is a function that returns a #GType of the plugin object.
          plugin_type is "auth" for authentication plugins and "account" for
          account plugins.
      </para>
      <para>
          If Tlm has been configured with --enable-debug, plugin directory can
          be overriden with TLM_PLUGINS_DIR environment variable.
      </para>
  </refsect1>
</refentry>
